A Guide to the René Jules Dubos papers, Rockefeller University Faculty FA122
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Manuscripts of various publications
  - Dubos. R.J. Celebrations of Life. McGraw-Hill Book Co., 1981; 5" letter. [GL 7/86.], 260 pp
    - Chapter III, 2 folders (Box 48, Folder 7-8)
      Titles and sub titles found in mss not same as in published book. Include various typescripts and handwritten copies. Also includes typescripts of Mss: "Global Thinking, Local Action" or "Thinking Globally, Acting Locally." René Dubos, The RU, Handwritten for SKF, Wall St Jl and Newsweek.
      Also: "The Despairing Optimist", No. 28, December 1977. (World Order vs The Assets of Diversity.) Handwritten note in pencil. "Used for World Order lect, U. of Delaware Jan. 12, 1978. Leroy Bennett.
    - Chapter IV, 1980 March 3; 5" letter [GL 7/86.] (Box 49, Folder 1)
      Titles and subtitles from mss not same as titles in published book.
      Includes various typescript and handwritten drafts.
      Also includes typescript and handwritten drafts of R.J. Dubos, "Adapting to The Future." (For Kenneth Labich, GEO Mag).
      René Dubos, "The Recycling of (Human) Nature (Only) the Past has a Future. In: Saturday Review/World, June 15, [Year?]. Galley proof with corrections.
      Adaptation Au Futur (In French). Typescript draft.
    - Chapter V (Box 49, Folder 2)
      Typescript and handwritten drafts.
    - Chapter VI, 2 folders (Box 49, Folder 3-4)
    - Correspondence, 1980 November 11 (Box 49, Folder 4)
      John Stevens, Editor of Leaders / Ruth Eblen, Nov. 11, 1980 w/Encl: galley proof of R.J. Dubos, "Shedding Light on a Thousand Devils (slug)" or "Learning from Success" (slug).
    - Dubos, "The Despairing Optimist III", Typescript draft (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Envoi (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Different text from one used in published book.
    - "The Despairing Optimist", no 20, 1975 June; Typescript draft (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Berth Jönsson, "The Volvo Experiences of New Job Design and New Production Technology", in Working Life in Sweden (Sept. 1980) no 19. Published by Swedish Information Service, 1980 September (Box 49, Folder 4)
    - Envoi (Box 49, Folder 4)
      Handwritten draft of text as published in book.
  - The Despairing Optimist, 2½" letter. [GL 7/86]
    - The Despairing Optimist, Vol. 1, Nos 1-17, by R.J. Dubos in American Scholar, 1972 1973 1974; Typescript of each, except reprint of no. 9 (Box 50, Folder 1)
      - Nos. 1-10, 1972
      - Nos. 11-14, 1973
      - Nos. 15-17, 1974
    - The Despairing Optimist, Nos 18-25 by R.J. Dubos, 1974 1975 1976; Various typescripts of each (Box 50, Folder 2)
      - Nos 18, 1974
      - Nos 19-22, 1975
      - Nos 23-25, 1976
    - The Despairing Optimist, Nos. 26-32 (1977, 1978, 1979) by R.J. Dubos, Typescripts of each (Box 50, Folder 3)
      - Nos. 26, 27, 28, 1977
      - Nos. 29, 30, 1978
      - Nos. 31, 32, 1979
- Book reviews of René J. Dubos books, 5" legal size. [GL 7/86.]
  Primarily newspaper, magazine and journal clippings of reviews, some are photocopies. Also includes typescripts of some reviews.
  Arranged in alphabetical order by title of book.
  - The Bacterial Cell (Box 51, Folder 1)
  - Bacterial and Mycotic Infections... (Box 51, Folder 2)
  - Beast or Angel? (Box 51, Folder 3)
  - Celebrations of Life (Box 51, Folder 4)
  - The Dream of Reason... (Box 51, Folder 5)
  - A God Within I (Box 51, Folder 6)
  - A God Within II (Box 51, Folder 7)
  - Louis Pasteur... (Box 51, Folder 8)
  - Man Adapting (Box 51, Folder 9)
  - Man, Medicine and Environment (Box 51, Folder 10)
  - Mirage of Health (Box 51, Folder 11)
  - Of Human Diversity (Box 51, Folder 12)
  - Only One Earth (Box 51, Folder 13)
  - The Professor, The Institute and DNA (Box 51, Folder 14)
  - Quest (Box 51, Folder 15)
  - Reason Awake (Box 51, Folder 16)
  - So Human an Animal (Box 51, Folder 17)
  - The Unseen World (Box 51, Folder 18)
  - The White Plague (Box 51, Folder 19)
  - The Wooing of Earth (Box 51, Folder 20)
- Interviews with R.J. Dubos and clippings about R.J. Dubos, and some by René J. Dubos, 1939-1970; 5" letter. [GL 7/86.]
  - Interviews with R.J. Dubos, 1967-1981
    - 1967-1978 April (Box 52, Folder 1)
    - 1978 - 1981 October (Box 52, Folder 2)
  - Clippings
    - 1939 (Box 52, Folder 3)
    - 1944 1946 (Box 52, Folder 4)
    - 1952 (Box 52, Folder 5)
    - 1954 (Box 52, Folder 6)
    - 1957 (Box 52, Folder 7)
    - 1959 (Box 52, Folder 8)
    - 1960 (Box 52, Folder 9)
    - 1961 (Box 52, Folder 10)
    - 1962 (Box 52, Folder 11)
    - 1963 (Box 52, Folder 12)
    - 1964 (Box 52, Folder 13)
    - 1965 (Box 52, Folder 14)
    - 1966 (Box 52, Folder 15)
    - 1967 (Box 52, Folder 16)
    - 1968 (Box 52, Folder 17)
    - 1969 (Box 52, Folder 18)
    - 1970 (Box 52, Folder 19)
  - Clippings, 1971-1982, undated; 5" letter [GL 7/86.]
    - 1971 (Box 53, Folder 1)
    - 1972 (Box 53, Folder 2)
    - 1973 (Box 53, Folder 3)
    - Cornell Medical College. Dubos, "Expectancy Revisited...", 1973 May 30 (Box 53, Folder 4)
    - 1974 (Box 53, Folder 5)
    - 1975 (Box 53, Folder 6)
    - 1976 (Box 53, Folder 7)
    - 1977 (Box 53, Folder 8)
    - 1978 (Box 53, Folder 9)
    - 1979 (Box 53, Folder 10)
    - 1980 (Box 53, Folder 11)
    - 1980 (Box 53, Folder 12)
    - 1981 (Box 53, Folder 13)
    - Therapaeia, "A Short History of DNA", 1981 February; pp 24, 25, 27, 29, 30, 31, 34, 35 (Box 53, Folder 14)
    - 1982 (Box 53, Folder 15)
    - undated (Box 53, Folder 16)
    - Country Journal clipping, undated (Box 53, Folder 17)
    - People Magazine clippings, undated (Box 53, Folder 18)
    - Multiple dates (Box 53, Folder 19)
- Subject Files, 5" letter. [7/86 GL.]
  Including grant material.
  - Health Research Council Grant and Annual Reports, 1962-1975 (Box 54, Folder 1)
  - NRC - HEW grant, 1963-1974 (Box 54, Folder 2)
    Includes grant application, efforts reports and correspondence.
  - Avery, O.T. (Box 54, Folder 3)
    Documents pertaining to O.T. Avery used by R.J. Dubos in his biography [of Avery] "The Professor, the Institute and DNA" [Note by Jean Dubos in folder] Included in folder is a mounted group photograph of O.T. Avery at Colgate.
  - René Dubos Forum Grant application in 1978 (Box 54, Folder 4)
    Bound duplicated copy.
  - René Dubos Center for Human Environment (formerly René Dubos Forum). Purpose, statements, releases etc. Photocopies (Box 54, Folder 5)
  - René Dubos Forum/René Dubos Center for Human Environment. Clippings, Newspaper and magazine. Originals and photocopies of (Box 54, Folder 6)
  - The René Dubos Forum, 1977 Sept. 8-11 symposium, "The Greening of Energy", 1977 September 8-11 (Box 54, Folder 7)
    2 printed pamphlets including:.
    Dubos, "Opening Address" and "Summary Statement". Text of and list of participants.
  - The René Dubos Forum. TV Pilot symposium, 1977 November 29 (Box 54, Folder 8)
    Printed notice of meeting, TV Pilot symp with participants.
  - The René Dubos Forum. Luncheon at The Harvard Club, NY City, 1978 May 10 (Box 54, Folder 9)
    Luncheon Program and guests. Presiding. René Dubos, Chairman.
  - The René Dubos Forum. 1980 Feb. Mar., Apr. symposiums on "Energy and the Way We Live: A National Issues Forum", 1980 February-April (Box 54, Folder 10)
    Program w/participants and abstracts of presentations. Feb. 10-16, Dubos, "Energy Supplies: Their Relation to Human Life and to the Environment. Abstract of.
  - The René Dubos Forum. 1980 June 15-17, Corvallis, Oregon State University. Symposium on Restoration of the Willamette River. "The Renaissance of a River." June 15, Dubos. Opening Address. "Wooing the Earth", 1980 September 5 (Box 54, Folder 11)
    Includes program and press release, 5 Sept. 1980 re René Dubos Center for Human Environments.
  - René Dubos Center for Human Environments (René Dubos Forum) (Box 54, Folder 12)
    - NY City, Waldorf Astoria. Convocation honoring Barbara Ward arid R.J. Dubos] as described by Jean Dubos], 1983 February 23-24
      Includes photocopies of N.Y. Times clipping, correspondence re convocation and invitations to with replies.
    - Also includes photocopies of news release and correspondence re 1982 Jan. 13, TV film by PBS. René Dubos in "Landscapes of Hope", 1982 January 13
  - The René Dubos Forum, March 25, 1980. "Adaptation au Futur - Place et Role de la Médecine", Montpelier (invitation to the forum), 1980 March 25 (Box 54, Folder 12a)
  - Tudor City Parks, Protection of, 1979 August (Box 54, Folder 13)
    Concerns preservation of Tudor City Parks. Originals and photocopies of 1981 correspondence primarily by tenants to RJD, as a member of Parks Council Board of Directors. In alphabetical order. Also includes Aug. 1979 list of The Parks Council, Bd of Directors.
  - The Global 2000 Report, 5" letter. [GL 7/86.]
    re René J. Dubos' disapproval of..
    Files consist of newspaper clips (some photocopies), correspondence, various typescripts of R.J. Dubos manuscripts, published articles by others, and published bound material - some of it background material and then The 2000 Global Report in 3 volumes.
    - The Global 2000 Report, 1908 March-1981 August, undated; 2 folders (Box 55)
      Materials collected prior to/about The Global 2000 Report. Includes published articles and editorials, correspondence and photocopies of mss.
    - IFIAS (The International Federation of Institutes for Advanced Study) (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Update, Programmes - Publications - Events, 1980-1981; 43 pp booklet. (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Resources, No. 66 24 pp publication by Resources For the Future, Spring 1981 (Box 55, Folder 1)
    - Published material (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Philip H. Abelson. Metallogenesis in Latin America. Science 207. 1157, 1980 March 14 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Editor's Page. Prospects for R & D in the eighties, 1980 July 28 (Box 55, Folder 2)
      C & E N [Chemical and Engineering News] (July 28, 1980) p. 9.
    - ? Environment. Toward a Troubled 21st Century. Time, p. 54, 1980 August 4 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Philip H. Abelson. The Global 2000 Report. Editorial. Science 209, 1980 August 15 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - The Nation's Health. American Public Health Assoc. Newspaper, 1980 September (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Le Monde, pp 3-6, 1980 October (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - The Other Side, No 21, 1980 December (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Julian Simon/Dubos. Encl. Galley proof (photocopy of) January 1981. Julian L. Simon. Global Confusion 1980. A Hard Look at the Global 2000 Report, circa 1908 December 31 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - John B. Oakes, An Insecurity Budget. New York Times, 1981 February 17; Photocopy (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - [Prof. Julian Simon] Simon Says. A global report is otherworldly. Time, March 9, 1981 p. 18, 1981 March 9 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Lyn Nofziger/Tom McCall, re an environmental advisor to President, 1981 March 9; Photocopy (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Mss by Emery N. Castle: Sharing the Earth. No Easy Answers, 1981 February 1981 April (Box 55, Folder 2)
      Photocopy Information. The Human Resource. Printed Booklet.
    - Clement Bezold/Dubos re Dubos, May 8, Wall St. J. article "Half-Truths About the Future", 1981 May 20 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Marion Clawson/Dubos w/Enclosure. Photocopy of: Marion Clawson, "Entering the twenty-first century - The Global/2000 report to the President", 1981 June 2 (Box 55, Folder 2)
    - Dubos. Improved Health is Bad for Your Health, 1980 October; typescript and handwritten copies. (Box 55, Folder 3)
    - Comments and Notes (Box 55, Folder 4)
      - René J. Dubos comments on Global 2000 Report... Drafts and working materials, 1981 February
      - René J. Dubos notes. Various drafts and working material
    - Dubos, R.J. (Box 55, Folder 5)
      - The Global 2000 Report to the President - Entering the 21st Century. [Pencilled by René J. Dubos - "Op-Ed Reduced as sent to Chandler Corben?, New York Times, March 3, 1981], 1981 March 3
      - untitled, Typescript and working materials
      - 1982 July (as identified by Jean Dubos) [July 1982]
      - Manuscript René J. Dubos submitted to New York Times Op-Ed. Not published. Possibly published by Wall St. Journal, 1981 March; Typescript
    - Dubos, René, 1981 May 8 (Box 55, Folder 6)
      Half-Truths About the Future. May 8, 1981, Wall Street Journal.
    - Dubos mss, Photocopy of published ms and photocopied typescripts (Box 55, Folder 6)
      Includes: Entering the 21st Century (part published in Wall St. J. and Re-Industrialization - Its Environmental Constraints and Potentialities.
    - After May 8, 1981. Yost, Nicholas C. Global 2000 Defended. Wall Street. Journal. News clip, 1981 May 8 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Dubos/George M. Woodwell, Director, MBL re Woodwell's criticism of Dubos Wall Street Journal article and Dubos defense. Photocopy of 3 pp letter w/working material, 1981 June 10 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Boffey, Philip M. Will the Next 20 Years Bring Prosperity or Decline? New York Times, Science Section. Newsclip. [re meeting w/authors of Global Report and those who opposed Report], 1982 January 12 (Box 55, Folder 6)
    - Dubos, R.J. "The myth of post-industrialization", 1981 May 13 (Box 55, Folder 7)
      Presentation, 13 May 1981, St. Louis, Mo., American Mining Congress.
      Typescripts and working drafts.
      [In pencil by J.D. [Jean Dubos]. "To be restructured from the two papers sent to the Wall Street Journal on April 9"].
      [Entering the 21st Century Reindustrialization] J.D.
      NYC, National Association of Biology Teachers Convention.
      Mirsky "Interaction between genes and environment".
      Partially typed and handwritten text.
      Scheduled to speak.
      [See also box no 44].
    - Mss by others (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Marion Clawson. The Global 2000 Report
      - Ernest Schneider. An Analysis of Global 2000
      - Ernest Schneider. What's Wrong with Global 2000?
      - Max Singer. The Scarcity "Error" as an Error
    - Published bound material (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - King, Alexander, Editor, "The State of the Planet". A report prepared for the International Federation of Institute for Advanced Study (IFIAS), Stockholm, Pergamon Press, 1980. 130 pp (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Environmental Education Report, 1981 January; 17 pp pamphlet. (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - The Global 2000 Report to the President. Entering the 21st Century. Vol 1. 2 copies w/Dubos handwritten notes on cover and inside, 1980 July 24 (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - Global Future: Time to Act. Report to the President on Global Resources, Environment and Population. Vol II, 1981 January (Box 55, Folder 8)
      - The Global 2000 Report to the President Vol III. Documentation on the Government's Global Sectoral Models: The Government's "Global Models", 1981 April (Box 55, Folder 8)
    - Commentary on Global 2000, by Herman Kahn and Ernest Schneider. Research Memorandum #102, "Carter's Global 2000 Swan Song: Crying Wolf to Rave Notices". Published by Hudson Institute, 1981 February (Box 55, Folder 9)
- Conferences, meetings, symposiums, seminars, interviews, reception for, awards to and induction to new membership in and photographic exhibit re "Celebrations of Life", 1981; 5" letter [GL 7/86]
  Files consist of news releases, newsletters, announcements and titles of R.J. Dubos presentations. Includes printed programs and tentative schedule of program, photocopies and printed copies of mss of Dubos presentations, some correspondence and biographical information re Dubos, publications containing photographs of slides used in presentations. Also includes a bound volume of the Proceedings of a conference, invitations, book lists and course outline, Dubos photograph and transcript of conversation (interview) with Bill. Moyers on Channel 13 in 1981. Same material not in each folder.
  - New York City, Hunter College, History of Science Society, Metropolitan New York Section meeting. [Slides for Dubos presentation, "Ars Medicus" available with other slides], 1959 October 22 (Box 56, Folder 1)
  - The Squibb Centennial Lecture Program, circa 1959 December (Box 56, Folder 2)
    [See also bound volume "The Centennial Lectures Commemorating the 100th Anniversary of E.R. Squibb & Sons", 1959. G.P. Putnam's Sons, New York].
  - New York City, American Orthopsychiatric Association annual meeting address, 1961 March 23 (Box 56, Folder 3)
  - Cincinnati, Ohio, University of Cincinnati. AAAS Holiday Science Lectures. [Based on R.J. Dubos RU Christmas Lectures in 1959], 1962 April 23-27 (Box 56, Folder 4)
  - Salmon Memorial Lectures. Publications containing photographs of slides used in presentation only, circa 1962 (Box 56, Folder 5)
  - Middletown, Conn, Wesleyan University, Center for Advanced Studies. Monday evening papers, 1963-1964 (Box 56, Folder 6)
  - Seattle, Washington, Arches of Science Award from the Pacific Science Center to Dubos, 1966 October 19 (Box 56, Folder 7)
  - New York City, Columbia University College of Physicians and Surgeons lecture series, 1967 November 6-9 (Box 56, Folder 8)
  - Warrentown, Va. The National Conference on Mental Health in Public Health Training. Bound volume of Proceedings of Conference only, 1968 May 27-30 (Box 56, Folder 9)
  - Kingston, Ontario, Queen's University Symposium, 1968 May 7 (Box 56, Folder 10)
  - New York City, Harvard Club. Dinner of the International Institute for the Study of Human Reproduction for Dr. René Dubos, 1969 October 23 (Box 56, Folder 11)
  - New York City, Firing Line on "Ecology" Wm. Buckley, Moderator, 1971 January 7 (Box 56, Folder 12)
  - London, Royal Society lecture, 1971 April 5 (Box 56, Folder 13)
  - Seminars at SUNY Purchase and at Staten Island College (City University), Richmond, Staten Island, 1971 (Box 56, Folder 14)
  - Stockholm, Sweden. UN Conference on Environment, 1972 June (Box 56, Folder 15)
  - New York City, Rockefeller University, Scientists' Committee for Public Information SCPI) meeting, 1972 September 11 (Box 56, Folder 16)
  - Washington, DC AAAS annual meeting. B.Y. Morrison Memorial Lecture, 1972 December 29 (Box 56, Folder 17)
  - New York City, Statler-Hilton Hotel. 1st Annual Meeting of the American Lung Association. James E. Perkins lecture by Dubos, 1973 May 20 (Box 56, Folder 18)
  - New York City, Cornell University Medical College commencement address, 1973 May 30 (Box 56, Folder 19)
  - Washington, DC (?), 75th National Meeting of Sigma Xi, 1974 November (?) (Box 56, Folder 20)
  - New York City, Institute for the Study of Human Knowledge/NYU School of Continuing Education. Symposium on Human Ecology, 1977 April 24 (Box 56, Folder 21)
  - Boston, Mass. Boston University Boston University Gerontology Center/American Geriatics Society meeting, 1977 September 27 (Box 56, Folder 22)
  - New York City, CUNY Graduate Center. Dubos. Newman lecturer and Newman award recipient, 1977 November 18 (?) (Box 56, Folder 23)
  - Seattle, Washington, University of Washington. Dubos. Danz Lecturer, 1978 March 27-April 14 (Box 56, Folder 24)
  - San Francisco, Calif. San Francisco Museum of Modern Art. lecture, 1978 April 16 (Box 56, Folder 25)
  - New York City, Cosmopolitan Club, Roosevelt Hospital Dept of Medicine address, 1978 May 9 (Box 56, Folder 26)
  - Boston, Mass. Human Ecology symposium sponsored by the Institute for the Study of Human Knowledge, 1978 May 13 (Box 56, Folder 27)
  - Ohio State University College of Medicine. Annual AOA lecture, 1978 May 22 (Box 56, Folder 28)
  - Madison, Wisconsin, University of Wisconsin. Aldo Leopold Memorial Colloquium address, 1978 June 21 (Box 56, Folder 29)
  - New York City, Fordham University 2nd annual Theodore Brameld lecture, 1978 October 21 (Box 56, Folder 30)
  - New York City, American Academy and Institute of Arts and Letters. Dubos inducted as member in dept of literature, 1979 May 23 (Box 56, Folder 31)
  - New York City, Queens College. Baccalaureate Convocation. Inauguration of Saul Bernard Cohen as President of Queens College, 1979 June 11 (Box 56, Folder 32)
  - New York City, Cathedral of St. John the Divine address, 1979 October 28 (Box 56, Folder 33)
  - New York City, Rockefeller University, RU Council meeting address, 1980 June 12 (Box 56, Folder 34)
  - New York City, Dag Hammarskjold Lounge of United Nations Plaza reception, 1980 July 29 (Box 56, Folder 35)
  - New York City, Barnard College. Samuel R. Milbank lecture, 1980 October 8 (Box 56, Folder 36)
  - New York City, New York Hilton Hotel. Celebration of R.J. Dubos 80th birthday. Outline of remarks by R.J. Dubos, 1981 January 8 (Box 56, Folder 37)
  - WNET/Channel 13, Bill Moyers' Journal. Conversation with Bill Moyers. "René Dubos: The Despairing Optimist at 80", 1981 February 20 (Box 56, Folder 38)
  - Philadelphia, Pa. University of Pennsylvania. Saturday at the University lecture, 1981 March 7 (Box 56, Folder 39)
  - New York City, The Four Seasons restaurant. France-American Society luncheon honoring Dr. Dubos, 1981 May 19 (Box 56, Folder 40)
  - Brasilia, Brazil. University of Brasilia celebration of 20 anniversary of University of Brasilia. "Dubos and Ecology", 1981 September 14-18 (Box 56, Folder 41)
  - New York City. The Cathedral Church of St. John the Divine address, 1981 October 25 (Box 56, Folder 42)
  - Martin, Tenn. University of Tennessee lecture, 1981 October 25 (Box 56, Folder 43)
  - Washington, DC 7th Intl symposium Smithsonian Institute. November 8. Presentation by Dubos. Tentative schedule, 1981 November 8-12 (Box 56, Folder 44)
  - New York City. Symposium "The Healing Brain III" sponsored by Pacific Medical Center/The Institute for the Study of Human Knowledge. Dec. 12. Presentation by Dubos, 1981 December 12-13 (Box 56, Folder 45)
  - New York City, Wave Hill. Photographic exhibit illustrating theme of Dubos " Celebrations of Life", 1982 February 10 (Box 56, Folder 46)
- Laboratory notes in laboratory notebooks, 1940-1944 1954-1955 1959 1968 undated; 2 boxes
  - Laboratory notebooks primarily 1940's and 1 notebook 1950's "on tuberculosis? " GL 7/86, 1940-1950; 8 folders, 5" letter
    - Gram Negative Bacilli, 1940 October-1942 January (Box 57, Folder 1)
    - Gramicidin Experiments, 1941 June-1942 March (Box 57, Folder 2)
    - R Shiga experiments, 1942 March-December 1943 January-April (Box 57, Folder 3)
    - New Mouse Graphs. Experiments 241-242 - 243-244, 1942 November (Box 57, Folder 4)
    - Experiments - Media 11 - Mouse, Agglutination, etc., 1942 December-1943 December (Box 57, Folder 5)
    - 1943 June-1944 May 1944 August (Box 57, Folder 6)
    - Old Mouse Graphs. DCA Gram Stains, 1943-1944 (Box 57, Folder 7)
    - "tuberculosis", 1954 July-December 1955 July-August (Box 57, Folder 8)
  - Laboratory notes, 1942-1943 1959 1968 undated; 3 folders; 2½" letter [GL 7/86]
    Laboratory notebooks.
    - Neutral Red Etc, 1942 April 1943 April-June 1959 August 1-October (Box 58, Folder 1)
      Amino acids in the reproduction of blood constituents in rats.
      J. Nutrition 47 (1952) 477-486.
      Includes reprints. Sebrel, W.H. and McDaniel, E.C.
    - Experiments with D & G & acid water. 20c + Mg. diet and acid H₂O, 1968 November-December (Box 58, Folder 2)
    - Undated. Experiments D & G. (Box 58, Folder 3)
  - Printed material, Assorted dates; 5" letter [GL 7/86.] (Box 59, Folder 3)
    Includes materials on Art and Psychiatry. In 6 folders. [See also: 5x7 negatives of some of these prints in Boxes (61) & (62).].
  - Photographic Prints, 4 folders; 2½" letter [GL 7/86]
    - History of Science and Medicine (Box 60, Folder 1)
      [See also: 5x7 negs "History of Science and Medicine" in Box (61)].
    - Portraits of Scientists (Box 60, Folder 2)
      [See also: 5x7 negs Portraits of Scientists in Box (62)].
    - Psychiatry in Art (Box 60, Folder 3)
      [See also: 5x7 negs "Psychiatry in Art" in Box (62)].
    - Miscellaneous prints (Box 60, Folder 4)